Finding Aid for the Preston Sturges Papers LSC.1114
UCLA Library Special Collections
Preston Sturges papers
1920-1959
UCLA Library Special Collections
Sturges, Preston
LSC.1114
57.5 Linear Feet (101 boxes and 7 cartons)
4 Born-digital Carriers (4 optical discs)
6 Audiovisual Carriers (6 videocassettes)
Preston Sturges (1898-1959) was a inventor, playwright and motion picture writer and director. He wrote the hit Broadway play, Strictly dishonorable (1929), and received a Academy Award for his screenplay, The great McGinty (1940). He lived in Europe for a period of time during the 1950s, and wrote and directed his last film in France in 1955. The collection consists of film scripts, production material, and correspondence related to Sturges' career.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Preston Sturges, 1975.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9932223513606533
Biographical / Historical
Born August 29, 1898 in Chicago as Edmond Preston Biden; inventor of kissproof lipstick for mother's cosmetic company; wrote hit Broadway play, Strictly dishonorable, 1929; moved to Hollywood, 1933; worked as screenwriter, and beginning in 1940 as a writer-director of satiric comedies; Academy Award for screenplay The great McGinty, 1940; left Paramount Pictures in 1944, and had a short business association with Howard Hughes, founding California Pictures in mid-1940s; lived in Europe for a period of time during the 1950s, writing and directing his last film in France in 1955; died in New York of heart attack on August 6, 1959.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of film scripts, production material, and correspondence related to Sturges' career as a playwright and motion picture writer and director.
Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Film productions.
Production material.
Business and personal material.
Correspondence.
Production scrapbooks.
Film scripts.; Dramatists, American -- Archives.; Screenwriters -- United States -- Archives.; Motion picture producers and directors -- United States -- Archives.; Scrapbooks.; Sturges, Preston--Archives.
- Film Productions
  General note
  Arranged by Charles Ziarko.
  - The Beautiful Blond from Bashful Bend., 1949
    (Also known as: Teacher's Pet; The Blond From Bashful Bend; The Lady From Laredo)
    - Studio correspondence and notes. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Studio correspondence with Darryl Zanuck. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Incomplete treatment., February 18, 1947. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Lady From Laredo By Earl Felton. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Script., August 20, 1947.; (two copies - 1 incomplete). (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - The Blond From Bashful Bend., [Bound volume]. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Script., October 8, 1947.; (2 copies). (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Teacher's Pet., [Bound volume]. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Script., December 29, 1947. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Teacher's Pet., [Bound volume]. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Script., January 13, 1948.; (2 copies). (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Script., September 7, 1948.; (2 copies. 1 with Zanuck notes) [Bound volume]. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Script., September 20, 1948.; (3 copies) [Bound volume]. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Script., September 23, 1948.; (2 copies). [Bound volume]. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Script., December 20, 1948.; [Bound volume]. (Box 3, Folder 2)
      (New ending).
    - Page changes., December 28, 1948.; (2 copies). (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Script copies with handwritten changes.
    - Yellow pages., June 11, 1947-December 19, 1948. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Revisions and notes handwritten. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 6: Two song sheets: In The Gloaming; Every Time I Meet You. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Christmas In July., 1940
    (Also known as: The New Yorkers; A Cup Of Coffee; Something To Shout About)
    - Correspondence. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Studio correspondence and notes. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous:, 1931-1934. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Script. A Cup Of Coffee., 1931.; [Bound volume]. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Script. Including story outline. (Incomplete) A Cup Of Coffee., March 10, 1935.; [Bound volume]. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Script. 3 act play A Cup Of Coffee., January 5, 1940.; [Bound volume]. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Script. 3 act play A Cup Of Coffee., January 23, 1940.; [Bound volume]. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Discards., February 14, 1940.; [Bound volume]. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Script., May 1, 1940.; [Bound volume]. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Script. The New Yorkers., May 9, 1940.; [Bound volume]. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Script. The New Yorkers., May 23, 1940.; [Bound volume]. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Yellow pages., April 29-June 19, 1940. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Musical score., April 29, 1941.; [Bound volume]. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - The Great Mcginty., 1940
    (Also known as: Down Went McGinty; Biography Of A Bum; The Story of A Man; The Vagrant)
    - Financial Data. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Script. The Vagrant. Redated Down Went McGinty., July 19, 1933. April 28, 1939.; [Bound volume]. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Script, The Story Of A Man., (original typed copy). [Bound volume]. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Discards A - C. Down Went McGinty., September 28-November 19, 1939.; [Bound volume]. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Discards D - E. Down Went McGinty., October 21-31, 1939.; [Bound volume]. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Discards F - J. Down Went McGinty., November 2-14, 1939.; [Bound volume]. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Script. Down Went McGinty., October 3-November 13, 1939. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Script. Down Went McGinty., November 13, 1939.; [Bound volume]. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Script. Down Went McGinty., November 14, 1939.; (Typed copy). [Bound volume]. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Script., November 28, 1939.; [Bound volume]. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Yellow pages and casting notes. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Musical score., May 23, 1940.; [Bound volume]. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The Great Moment., 1944
    (Also known as: Great Without Glory; Triumph Over Pain; The Life of William T.G. Morton)
    - Treatment., Samuel Hofrenstein. The Life Of William T.G. Morton, synopsized., Richard Blumenthal., July 1, 1938 August 24, 1939; [Bound volume]. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Research notes. Triumph Over Pain., n.d.; 157pp. [Bound volume]. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Script. - incomplete. Triumph Over Pain., July 13, 1939; [Bound volume]. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 1st draft discards and notes. Triumph Over Pain., August 1, 1939.; [Bound volume]. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Script. Triumph Over Pain., August 2, 1939.; [Bound volume]. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 2nd version discards and notes. Triumph Over Pain., August 16, 1939.; [Bound volume]. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Script. Triumph Over Pain., September 13, 1939.; [Bound volume]. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Script. Triumph Over Pain., December 15, 1939.; [Bound volume]. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Script. Triumph Over Pain., March 30, 1942.; [Bound volume]. (Box 110)
    - Script., April 3, 1942; (2 copies - incomplete). (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Great Without Glory., [Bound volume]. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Production script no.1337. Great Without Glory., [Bound volume]. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Positive film in Box 111.
    - Yellow pages (by date). (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Dialogue continuity., June 10, 1942; (2 copies). (Box 110)
    - Great Without Glory., [Bound volume]. (Box 110)
    - Laugh meter notes. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Musical score. Great Without Glory., September 23, 1942.; [Bound volume]. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Hail The Conquering Hero., 1944
    (Also known as: The Little Marine; Once A Hero)
    - Correspondence., 2 pieces. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Treatment. (two copies - redated )., June 7, 1943 June 11, 1943; [Bound volume]. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Same., June 12, 1943.; [Bound volume]. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Script. The Little Marine., June 21, 1943.; [Bound volume]. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Script. (incomplete - with changes). The Little Marine., July 12, 1943; [Bound volume]. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Synopsis. (redated ). The Little Marine Allida Allan., June 21, 1943 August 4, 1943; [Bound volume]. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Script. (Incomplete). The Little Marine., July 8, 1943; [Bound volume]. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Added scenes and retakes., March 30, 1944.; (3 copies). (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Dialogue continuity., September 20, 1943.; [Bound volume]. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Laugh meter notes and preview comments. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Yellow pages (by date)., May 29-July 8, 1943. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous notes -, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Musical score., January 15, 1944.; [Bound volume]. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - If I Were King., 1938
    - Original play, Justin Huntum McCarthy (Samuel French edition)., (Bound volume). (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Revised pages., February 2-August 30, 1938. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Original notes., April 15, 1938.; [Bound volume]. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Script., February 2-April 18, 1938.; [Bound volume]. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Script. (A - C incomplete)., February 2-March 1938.; [Bound volume]. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Script. (D - E incomplete)., February 27-March 28, 1938.; [Bound volume]. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Script. (F - J incomplete)., March 28-April 13, 1938.; [Bound volume]. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Script., with letter from Frank Lloyd., April 11, 1938; [Bound volume]. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Script., May 7, 1938.; [Bound volume]. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Screen credit documentation., 5 pieces. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - The Lady Eve., 1941
    (Also known as: Two Bad Hats)
    - Correspondence. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Discards., August 26, 1940.; [Bound volume]. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Original script. Two Bad Hats., September 9-December 2, 1938.; [Bound volume]. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Discards A - D. Two Bad Hats., September 14-October 15, 1938.; [Bound volume]. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Discards E - End. Two Bad Hats., October-December 1938.; [Bound volume]. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Script. Two Bad Hats., September 20-November 29, 1938.; [Bound volume]. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Script., October 7, 1940.; [Bound volume]. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Script., October 18, 1940.; [Bound volume]. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Production script., October 18, 1940.; [Bound volume]. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Notes. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Studio correspondence. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Dialogue continuity., n.d.; [Bound volume]. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Laugh meter notes. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Musical score., April 29, 1941.; [Bound volume]. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Look, Ma - I'm Dancin'! (Unproduced: ), 1952
    [c.f. Box 20].
    - Original script (Incomplete). (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Notes and set sketches., Jerome Robbins., April 11-21, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Script., Joe Sistrom., December 18, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Scenario (), Jerome Robbins & Arthur Laurents., n.d. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Memo (), Laurence Stallings., n.d. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Note (), Preston Sturges., n.d. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - First Effort, February 10, March 4, 1952. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Script., April 21, 1952. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Intermediate script., (Incomplete)., June 1952 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Script., May 5, 1952.; 52 typed pages (Incomplete). (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Script., June 23, 1952.; 114pp. (two copies incomplete). (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Script., July 10, 1952.; [Bound volume]. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Look Ma yellow pages. (by date)., February 24-July 10, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Look Ma discard pages. (by date)., April 15-June 30, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Look Ma discard pages, 1-115., June 1952. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Mad Wednesday., 1950
    (Also known as: The Sin of Harold Diddlebock; The Saga of Harold Diddlebock)
    - Typed satire The Sin Of Harold Diddlebock. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Laugh meter notes and preview notes. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Typed copy of script, January 18-April 24, 1945. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Script., May 2, 1945.; [Bound volume]. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Script. With revisions to, May 2, 1945. August 28, 1945. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Revised pages., August 28, 1945. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Yellow pages. (by date)., October 22, 1944-February 28, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Yellow pages. (by date)., March 1-August 27, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous including handwritten notes (). (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Matrix (Unproduced: ), 1949-1958
    [c.f. Box 15]
    (Also known as: The Miracle of Morgan's Creek)
    - Financial data. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Script and synopsis., 1951. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Yellow pages (by date)., September 9-October 18, 1949; May 29, 1951-January 13, 1952; July 17-21, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Miracle revisions., July 15-November 23, 1942. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Miracle miscellaneous revisions, ()., n.d. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - The Miracle Of Morgan's Creek., 1944
    - Laugh meter notes. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Script., August 27-October 9 & October 14-16, 1942.; (Typescript). (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Script., September 10, 1942.; [Bound volume]. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Script., October 14, 1942; (2 copies). [Bound volume]. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Script., October 19, 1942.; (Incomplete) [Bound volume]. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Script., November 23, 1942.; (Incomplete) [Bound volume]. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Prop newspapers used in picture. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Musical score., March 5, 1943.; [Bound volume]. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Nothing Doing (Unproduced: ), 1949
    (Also known as: Mr. Big In Littleville; Love Among The Lobsters)
    - Correspondence. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Script., March 2-April 6, 1949.; (Incomplete) [Bound volume]. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Script., June 28, 1949.; [Bound volume]. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Script., August 1, 1949. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Script., August 23, 1949.; [Bound volume]. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Notes: handwritten (). (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Yellow pages. (by date)., January 22-31, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Yellow pages., February 1-September 7, 1949. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Yellow page carbons., August 12-21, 1949.; (Incomplete) [Bound volume]. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - The Palm Beach Story., 1942
    (Also known as: Is That Bad?; Is Marriage, Necessary?)
    - Correspondence. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Laugh meter notes. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Notes and discards (). (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Script., November 3, 1941.; [Bound volume]. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Script., November 8, 1941.; [Bound volume]. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Yellow pages: complete script ()., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Dialogue continuity., February 7, 1942.; [Bound volume]. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Yellow pages and notes., September 3-November 18, 1941. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Pencil sketch on envelope. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Musical score., May 6, 1942.; [Bound volume]. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - A Present For Uncle Popo (Unproduced)
    (Also known as: Birthday Gift)
    - Handwritten, two versions (Incomplete). (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Notes handwritten. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Wild sheets ()., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Discard pages in page order. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Script, Birthday Gift., 2 versions. [Bound volume]. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Yellow pages & notes: miscellaneous. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Remember The Night., 1940
    (Also known as: The Amazing Marriage; Beyond These Tears)
    - Studio correspondence. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Script sequence A. Beyond These Tears., January 4-February 17, 1939.; [Bound volume]. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Script seq. B - C. Beyond These Tears., February 12-March 1, 1939.; [Bound volume]. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Script sequence D - H. Beyond These Tears., March 1-21, 1939.; [Bound volume]. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Script. The Amazing Marriage., March 10, 1939.; [Bound volume]. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Script. The Amazing Marriage., March 24, 1939.; (two copies) [Bound volume]. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Script. The Amazing Marriage., June 15, 1939.; [Bound volume]. (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Yellow pages., May 31-June 8, 1939. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Roman Holiday., 1953
    - Script (SF 83316)., Ian McLellan Hunter. Revised., Lester King., March 1, 1950 June 11, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Script ()., n.d.; 174pp. mimeograph. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Script., Ben Hecht., July 10, 1951; (Incomplete) [Bound volume]. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Script., April 6, 1952.; Typed copy [Bound volume]. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Sturges notes. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Sturges notes and discards in original folder with sketches. (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Yellow pages: in order. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Sullivan's Travels., 1941
    - Laugh meter notes. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Script., February 3, 1941.; [Bound volume]. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Script., April 21, 1941.; Typescript. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Script., April 22, 1941.; [Bound volume]. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Script., May 3, 1941.; (2 copies) [Bound volume]. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Yellow pages., February 4-May-8, 1941. (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Dialogue continuity., July 22, 1941.; [Bound volume]. (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Musical score., November 4, 1941.; [Bound volume]. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Unfaithfully Yours., 1948
    (Also known as: The Symphony Story)
    - Laugh meter notes. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Studio Correspondence with Darryl Zanuck. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Script, original play ()., n.d.; [Bound volume]. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Script., December 2, 1947.; (2 copies) [Bound volume]. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Script., January 15, 1948.; (2 copies) [Bound volume]. (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Script., February 5, 1948.; 1st 47pp. only. [Bound volume]. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Script., including revisions to, February 5, 1948 February 10, 1948.; [Bound volume]. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Script., February 10, 1948.; (2 copies) [Bound volume]. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Revised pages. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Breakdown pages for Production Department. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous notes. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Scripts Written By P.S. During, 1930s
    [c.f. Box 31].
    - Script. The Big Pond., November 26, 1929.; 134 mimeographed pages [Bound volume]. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Script. Child of Manhattan, original binder with notes., 1931.; [Bound volume]. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - College Swing handwritten notes. (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Script. College Swing., November 4, 1937.; [Bound volume]. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Script. College Swing., November 15, 1937.; [Bound volume]. (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Script, The Crepe Hangar (Incomplete), handwritten with visual caricatures. (?) Forerunner of A Cup of Coffee and Christmas in July. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Script, Frank Marlowe (Incomplete), handwritten. (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - The Great Love,., Handwritten (Incomplete). (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Script., September 21, 1936.; Mimeograph (Incomplete). (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Script., September 25, 1936.; Mimeograph (Incomplete). (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - The Guinea Pig, 23 sides. (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - The Guinea Pig, correspondence, ads, notes. (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - On Approval., (Incomplete) typed copy. (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Narration script, The Power And The Glory. (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - The Power And The Glory, correspondence. (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Script, Recapture., (Incomplete). (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Recapture, correspondence. (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Script, So She Married The Jerk., Handwritten (Incomplete). (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Strictly Dishonorable., (Incomplete), pencil notes. (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Diamond Jim., May 6, 1935.; (Incomplete script). (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - The Good Fairy, notes, synopsis, censor memos. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - The Good Fairy, script., August 11, 1934. (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Script. Make A Wish (adaption of The Good Fairy)., November 16, 1950. (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - The Good Fairy., (3 incomplete copies - 1 with notes). (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Script. The Mine With The Iron Door., February 3-5, 1936.; 39 typed pages. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Song of Joy proposed cast sheet. Continuity suggestions for muscial numbers., February 27, 1941.; (3 copies). (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Script, Spinster Dinner. (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Script, William Counselman ()., n.d. (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Script, Preston Sturges ()., n.d.; [Bound volume]. (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Thirty Day Princess yellow pages (Incomplete). (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Script. We Live Again & Resurection., May 1934.; [Bound volume]. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Scripts Written for Paramount., 1936-1943
    - Beaucaire. notes., 1943 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Synopsis. Easy Living Vera Caspary., May 1,1935.; [Bound volume]. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Easy Living., Handwritten (Incomplete). (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Script. Easy Living., March 26, 1937.; (Incomplete) [Bound volume]. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Easy Living., Typed corrections. (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Hotel Haywire., Typed synopsis [Bound volume]. (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Hotel Haywird'treatment., March 29, 1937.; [Bound volume]. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Script, Hotel Haywire ()., n.d.; [Bound volume]. (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Yellow pages. Hotel Haywire., June 16, 1936. (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Script. Never Say Die., December 2, 1937-.; [Bound volume]. (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Script. New York Town., November 2-29, 1940.; [Bound volume]. (Box 28, Folder 11)
      (Sturges directed retakes).
    - Revised pages. New York Town (two copies)., March 8, 1941. (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - New York Town laugh meter notes. (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Script. Star Spangled Rhythm, Harry Tugend., May 20, 1942.; [Bound volume]. (Box 28, Folder 14)
      (Sturges appeared in cameo role).
    - Synopsis, The Diamond., 1943. (Box 28, Folder 15)
      (Also known as: Star of India; The Human Safe; Speaking of Operations; Human Strong Box)
  - I Married A Witch. and Vendetta., 1942 1950
    - Laugh meter notes. (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Studio correspondence. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Script, sequence A - B., Robert Arosn., January 12, 1942; [Bound volume]. (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Script, sequence C - End., Robert Arosn., March 3, 1942; [Bound volume]. (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Yellow pages, notes outline, typed copy of script., also:, February 4-April 8, 1942 n.d. (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Dialogue continuity., May 29, 1942.; [Bound volume]. (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Script. Vendetta, (Incomplete). Titles: Colomba., November 20, 1944-February 20, 1945.; [Bound volume]. (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Script. Vendetta., July 16-31, 1945.; [Bound volume]. (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Continuity, Vendetta (incomplete)., [Bound volume]. (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Treatment, Vendetta, (). Titled: Corsican Holdiay; Katherine Lanier; Paul De Saint Colombe., [Bound volume]. (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Wild sheets, Vendetta., June 2-July 31, 1946. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Scripts Written By P.S. During, 1950s
    - Folders 1 - 6: The French - They Are A Funny Race
      (Also known as: Les Carnets Du Major Thompson)
      - Script., 126pp. in French. [Bound volume]. (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Script., 140pp. in English. [Bound volume]. (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Notes and photographs. (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Satiric newspaper article., (2 copies). (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence including telegrams. (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous. (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Script: Le Coffre - Fort Vivant, in French, performed., December 17, 1938. (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Le Coffre - Fort Vivant correspondence., 1956. (Box 30, Folder 8)